William N. Fenton Papers 1933-2000 Mss.Ms.Coll.20
American Philosophical Society
William N. Fenton Papers
ca. 1933-2000
Mss.Ms.Coll.20
American Philosophical Society
22.0 Linear feet
A Yale-educated ethnographer, William Fenton devoted most of his career to study of the Iroquois Indians of New York State and Canada. Receiving his doctorate in 1937, Fenton worked with the Bureau of American Ethnology for a number of years before becoming Director of the New York State Museum and professor at SUNY Albany. The Fenton Papers covers all aspects of William Fenton's professional life, documenting his varied positions as community worker for the New York Agency of the U.S. Indian Service, 1935-1937 (accounts, reports, correspondence); associate anthropologist and senior ethnologist in the Bureau of American Ethnology, 1939-1951 (includes notebooks, letters from the field); Executive Secretary of Anthropology and Psychology, National Academy of Sciences-National Research Council, 1952-1954; and Assistant Commissioner, New York State Museum and Science Service, 1954-1968.
22 linear feet
Fenton, William N., (William Nelson), 1908-2005
Biographical/Historical note
Born in New Rochelle, N.Y., on December 15, 1908, William Nelson Fenton, became a leading scholar of the history and culture of Iroquois Indians. Raised in New Rochelle until the age of 16, he passed his summers on the family farm in western New York state, located midway between two Seneca Indian reservations. Exposed to anthropological work, Fenton's interests were encouraged by his father and grandfather, friends to Indians there, who assembled a small collection of Indian memorabilia which was later acquired by the Museum of the American Indian.
After receiving his B.A. from Dartmouth in 1931, Fenton attended Yale for graduate study in anthropology. At the end of his first year in New Haven, the Laboratory of Anthropology at Santa Fe awarded him a scholarship for training in field archaeology on the Great Plains of Nebraska and South Dakota, where he took part in his first professional ethnological interviews. Returning to his old home in New York in 1933, Fenton embarked on what would become more than fifty years of field research on the Allegany, Cornplanter, Cattaraugus, and Tonawanda Seneca Reservations and on the Six Nations Reserve in Canada. From 1935 until he received his doctorate in 1937, Fenton also served as a community worker for the United States Indian Service, working principally on the Tonawanda Reservation.
In his first academic appointment in 1937, Fenton introduced anthropology to St. Lawrence University, though he remained for only three semesters before being called to replace J.N.B. Hewitt at the Bureau of American Ethnology (BAE) of the Smithsonian Institution, earning promotion to Senior Ethnologist in 1943. During the war years, he served as a Research Associate of the Ethnogeographic Board and as Secretary of the Smithsonian War Committee. While a member of the Committee on International Relations in Anthropology at the National Research Council (NRC) from 1952 to 1954, he served as the first Executive Secretary of the Division of Anthropology and Psychology. Meanwhile, he was employed as a visiting professor at Johns Hopkins, Northwestern, and Catholic Universities, and at the University of Michigan.
In 1954, Fenton returned to New York State with his wife, Olive (1908-1986), and their three children to become Assistant Commissioner of the New York State Museum and Science Service in Albany, serving as director of the State Museum for thirteen years. In 1968, he abandoned administration and returned to teaching as Research Professor of Anthropology at the State University of New York at Albany. In 1979, the trustees named him Distinguished Professor, and Anthony F.C. Wallace delivered the honorary lecture.
Throughout his career, Fenton's research centered on the religious ceremonies and customs of the Iroquois, epitomised by his translation (with Elizabeth Moore) of The Customs of the American Indian Compared with the Customs of Primitive Times by Father Joseph François Lafitau, and hy his most influential work, his 1987 book, The False Faces of the Iroquois.
Fenton received numerous awards, including the Peter Doctor Award of the Seneca Nation (1958), the Cornplanter Medal for Iroquois Research (1965), the Citizen Laureate Award of the University of Albany Foundation (1978), the Distinguished Service Award of the American Anthropological Association (1983), and an LL.D. from Hartwick College (1968). He was president of the American Folklore Society (1959-1960), the American Ethnological Society (1959), and the American Society for Ethnohistory (1961); a Board member of the American Anthropological Association; and a trustee of the Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation (1976-1989). He was a founder of the Conference on Iroquois Research in 1945, and a founding member of the SUNY Albany chapter of Sigma Xi. He was also a long-time member of the Phillips Fund Committee of the American Philosophical Society (1975-1991) and of the American Committee of the Permanent Council of the International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences (1952-1972), as well as Distinguished Professor Emeritus at the State University of New York at Albany. He passed away on June 17, 2005.
Scope and Contents note
The William N. Fenton Papers (1635-1994) contain correspondence, subject files, manuscripts of published and unpublished works by Fenton, papers by colleagues, research notes, and photographs, which document Fenton's career as an anthropologist. The most recent items in the collection are letters dated 1994. Documenting both Fenton's research on the Iroquois and the evolution of Iroquois studies, the collection also includes photocopies of primary materials dating back into the seventeeth century.
The Fenton Papers focus on Iroquois ethnology and political history, and include an important series of correspondence between Fenton and his Seneca consultants, Clara and Sherman Redeye and Jesse J. Cornplanter, 1933-1967, among others. Fenton also gathered works written by Cornplanter himself. Of related interest are a collection of Seneca genealogies; the extensive documentation of the protracted controversy between the Seneca Nation and the U.S. Government over the construction of the Kinzua Dam; and material concerning Fenton's controversial role in resisting early attempts at cultural repatriation waged by the Onondaga Indians in the "Great Wampum War of 1970" (restricted access; see: Fenton, "The New York State Wampum Collection: The Case for the Integrity of Cultural Treasures," APS Proceedings. 115:6, 1971).
Having been instrumental in their organization, Fenton kept a wealth of material on the Conferences on Iroquois Research, 1948-1966. Fenton's research on Iroquois ceremonial False Faces is documented by research notes, photographs, and a penultimate draft of the book manuscript, and his participation in international anthropological organizations is evidenced by the material on the International Union of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences. Of special note is the journal he kept for the VIIth International Congress which met in Moscow in 1964. There is also material on the Committee on International Relations in Anthropology, 1945-1950. A series of thirteen tape recordings of Seneca social dance songs (the originals of which are at the Indian University Archive of Folk and Primitive Music) rounds out the Iroquois material.
Among the miscellaneous materials in the collection are copies of the original, and unpublished, Iroquois field notebooks of Alexander A. Goldenweiser, taken at the Six National Reserve in Canada, 1911-1918. Edward Sapir, who supervised Goldenweiser's research, helped Fenton recover the originals, which Goldenweiser passed to Sapir's graduate students, and ultimately to Fenton in the 1930s. The originals were sent to the National Museum of Man in Canada during the 1970s. There is material concerning Fenton's preparation of these notebooks for publication, including a very informative introduction prepared by one of Fenton's graduate students.
The papers (107 boxes; 56.5 linear feet) are divided into seven series:
Series I. Correspondence 1897-1994 39 boxes; 19.25 linear feet
Series IIa. Subject files 1846-1992 15 boxes; 7.5 linear feet
Series IIb. Iroquois Documentary History Project 1635-1989 3 boxes; 1.5 linear feet
Series III. Works by Fenton 1711-1991 13 boxes; 6.25 linear feet
Series IV. Works by others 1848-1994 10 boxes; 4.5 linear feet
Series V. Research notes 1912-1981 17 boxes; 10.5 linear feet
Series VI. Photographs 1880-1993 12 boxes; 7 linear feet
Series I-VI. Oversized 1 box; 0.25 linear feet
Oversized materials follow the same series arrangement as noted above. Cross referencing to oversized material appears on the folders in the standard sized boxes. All photographs and negatives have been removed from Series I-V and placed in Series VI. Cross references appear in the original series. Reprints have been moved to the printed materials collection of the APS library. If a reprint was found as an enclosure, a photocopy of the title page was filed in its place. To retrieve reprints, consult the card catalog for printed materials. Microfiche, microfilm, and audio- and video-cassette recordings have also been removed from the collection; to retrieve those items, consult the card catalog for manuscript materials.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Fenton Papers have been donated by William N. Fenton between 1982 and 2000.
Separated Materials note
William N. Fenton, collector, n.d., [c.1984]. 1 audiocassette tape. Radio broadcast: "Manhattan at Large." Councilman Stanley Michaels, host. Topic: "The Future of the Museum of the American Indian." Guests: Dr. Edmund Carpenter, Anthropologist, Member Board of Trustees, Museum of the American Indian; Pamela Mann, Asst. N.Y., Attorney General; N.Y. Assemblyman Herman D. Farrell, Jr.; Randle Borshi, Deputy Commissioner, N.Y. City Dept. of Cultural Affairs.
William Fenton and David Sapir. Oct. 1, 1984. 1 VHS videocassette tape. Produced by Allan Burns. Dept. of Anthropology, University of Florida, Gainesville, Fla. 32611.
3 green vinyl records removed from Ser. II, International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences (7th: 1964: Moscow).
13 microfiche: 9 of correspondence between Edward Sapir and Alexander A. Goldenweiser, 1911-1925; 4 of correspondence between Edward Sapir and F.W. Waugh, 1912. Appears to be from the National Museums of Canada.
3 reels of microfilm (3 copies): Jesse J. Cornplanter and Joseph Keppler correspondence, 1900-1938, from Museum of the American Indian.
1 reel of microfilm: Samuel Wharton. Facts and observations respecting the country granted to his majesty by the Six Nations (London, 1775), 170 pp.+, from the Library of Congress, 3 Mar. 1952.
1 reel of microfilm: Du Simitiere Papers (1769); Christopher Sauer material (1749), from Historical Society of Pennsylvania.
Related Archival Materials note
Fenton's papers are among several collections pertaining to the history and culture of Iroquois Indians, including the papers of Elisabeth Tooker, Ely S. Parker, and Anthony F. C. and Paul A. W. Wallace.
Bibliography
Fenton, William N., The False Faces of the Iroquois (Norman: Univ. of Oklahoma, 1987). 970.3 F36f
Fenton, William N., ed., Parker on the Iroquois (Syracuse: Syracuse Univ., 1968). 970.3 P22i
Barbeau, C. Marius, 1883-1969; Buffalo Historical Society (Buffalo, NY).; Carpenter, Edmund, 1922-2011; Congdon, Charles E., (Charles Edwin), b. 1877; Cornplanter, Edward; Cornplanter, Jesse J.; Deardorff, Merle H., d.1971; Dodge, Ernest Stanley; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844; Erminie Wheeler-Voegelin, 1903-1988; Foster, Michael K.; Gibson, John Hardy; Gibson, Simeon; Goldenweiser, Alexander, 1880-1940; Graymont, Barbara; Hallowell, A. Irving, (Alfred Irving), 1892-1974; Harrington, M. R. (Mark Raymond), 1882-1971; Harris, Helen; Herskovits, Melville J., (Melville Jean), 1895-1963; Hewitt, J. N. B., (John Napoleon Brinton), 1859-1937; Hill, Cephas; Jamieson, Sadie; Jennings, Francis, 1918-; Johnny John, Chauncey; Keppler, Joseph; Kidder, Alfred Vincent, 1885-1963; Kurath, Gertrude Prokosch; Lafitau, Joseph-Francois, 1681-1746; Lévi-Strauss, Claude; Logan, Frank; Lounsbury, Floyd Glenn; McIlwraith, T. F. (Thomas Forsyth), 1899-; Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation; New York State Museum; Parker, Arthur Caswell, 1881-1955; Redeye, Clara; Redeye, Henry; Redeye, Sherman; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979; Royal Ontario Museum. Division of Art and Archaeology..; Sapir, Edward, 1884-1939; Snow, Jones; Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950; Spier, Leslie, 1893-1961; Sturtevant, William C.; Tooker, Elisabeth.; Trigger, Bruce G.; United States. Department of the Interior; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-; Wallace, Paul A. W.; Waugh, F. W., (Frederick Wilkerson), 1872-1924; White, Leslie A., 1900-1972; White, Marian E. (Marian Emily), 1921-1975; Wissler, Clark, 1870-1947; Witthoft, John; Woodbury, Hanni; Agendas; Anthropological museums and collections--Laws and legislation; Anthropologists.; Eagle dance; Eastern Woodlands Indians; Field notes.; Gelatin silver prints; Genealogies; Handsome Lake Code; Iroquois dance; Iroquois Indians--Games; Iroquois Indians--Religion; Iroquois Indians--Social life and customs; Iroquois masks; Kinzua Dam (N.Y. and Pa.); Lectures; Maps.; Minutes; Negatives; Notebooks; Seneca Indians; Seneca Indians--Genealogy; Seneca Indians--Music; Seneca Indians--Religion; Seneca Indians--Relocation; Seneca Indians--Social life and customs; Seneca masks; Wampum belts
- Series I. Correspondence, 1897-1994; 39 boxes; 19.25 linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  Incoming and outgoing manuscript and typescript letters, carbons, telegrams, and postcards generated during Fenton's career. The largest series in the collection, Series I is arranged alphabetically by correspondent's name and then chronologically within each folder. Unidentified correspondence has been filed as "Unidentified" and is arranged chronologically. Enclosed manuscripts have been removed from this series and placed in Series III or IV as appropriate. As with the reprints, a photocopy of the title page was filed with the original letter. The bulk of this series covers the years 1930 to 1993.
  Correspondents include anthropologists, government officials, students, publishers, Native Americans, and interested amateur anthropologists. Among the topics covered in this series are: Iroquois ceremonies and customs, relocation and administration of the Museum of the American Indian, and Smithsonian Institution's Bureau of American Ethnology. For lists of correspondence related to construction of Kinzua Dam and to wampum belts, see the folders labeled "Kinzua Dam" and "Wampum" in Series II. Material relevant to Fenton's work for the United States Indian Service is filed under "United States. Department of the Interior." Letters of reference are filed under the name of the person who is the subject of the letter. For lists of correspondence with colleagues about Fenton's publications, see Series III under the publications' titles.
  Barbeau, C. Marius
  Boas, Franz
  Carpenter, Edmund S.
  Congdon, Charles E.
  Deardorff, Merle H.
  Dodge, Ernest Stanley
  Foster, Michael K.
  Goldenweiser, Alexander A.
  Graymont, Barbara
  Hallowell, Alfred Irving
  Harrington, Mark Raymond
  Herskovits, Melville J.
  Hewitt, J.N.B.
  Jennings, Francis P.
  Kemp, Jack
  Kennedy, Robert F.
  Keppler, Joseph
  Kidder, Alfred V. II
  Kurath, Gertrude Prokosch
  Levi-Strauss, Claude
  Logan, Frank
  Lounsbury, Floyd G.
  McIlwraith, Thomas F.
  Mead, Margaret
  Parker, Arthur C.
  Rockefeller, Nelson A.
  Sapir, Edward
  Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr.
  Shimony, Annemarie
  Speck, Frank G.
  Spier, Leslie
  Sturtevant, William C.
  Tooker, Elisabeth
  Trigger, Bruce G.
  Voegelin, Erminie
  Wallace, Anthony F.C.
  Wallace, Paul A.W.
  Waugh, F.W.
  White, Leslie A.
  White, Marian E.
  Wissler, Clark
  Witthoft, John
  Woodbury, Hanni J.
  Also included in this series is correspondence from several Native Americans detailing reservation life, customs, and ceremonies.
  Principal correspondents include:
  Cornplanter, Edward
  Cornplanter, Jesse J.
  Gibson, John Hardy
  Gibson, Simeon
  Harris, Helen
  Hill, Cephas D.
  Jamieson, Sadie
  Redeye, Clara
  Redeye, Sherman
  Sky, Howard
  - Aaron, Daniel, 1982 (Box Series I-1)
  - Abbett, Robert W. (Box Series I-1)
    -See Ser. I, Morgan, Arthur E.
  - Abbot, C.G. (Box Series I-1)
    -See Ser. I, Smithsonian Institution
    -See Ser. I, Strong, William Duncan
  - Aberle, Sophie D., 1958 (Box Series I-1)
  - Abler, Thomas S., 1965, 1968, 1986, 1988-1992 (Box Series I-1)
    -See also Ser. I, American Ethnologist (1992)
  - Abrams, Cornelius, 1945, 1947 (Box Series I-1)
  - Abrams, George H.J., 1966-1994 (Box Series I-1)
    Eggan, Fred
    -See also Ser. I, Carpenter, Edmund S.
    -See also Ser. I, Eggan, Fred
    -See also Ser. I, Museum of the American Indian
    -See also Ser. I, Seneca-Iroquois National Museum
  - Abrams, Robert (Box Series I-1)
    -See Ser. I, Museum of the American Indian
  - Academy of Independent Scholars, 1986-1987 (Box Series I-1)
  - Academy of Sciences of the U.S.S.R., 1943 (Box Series I-1)
  - Adams, Charles C., 1936-1943, 1954 (Box Series I-1)
  - Adams, Harriet Dyer, 1972, 1993 (Box Series I-1)
  - Adams, Percy G. (Box Series I-1)
    -See Ser. I, Sturtevant, William C.
  - Adams, Spencer L., 1943-1944 (Box Series I-1)
  - Adams, Walter Randolph, 1977 (Box Series I-1)
  - American Philosophical Society (Box Series I-1)
  - Adirondack Conference Centers, 1966 (Box Series I-1)
    Jones, Richard A.
  - Adirondack Park, 1989 (Box Series I-1)
  - Adney, E. Tappan, 1944 (Box Series I-1)
    -See also Ser. I, Deardorff, Merle H. (1944)
  - Aerovias Brazil, 1954 (Box Series I-1)
  - African Studies Center, 1969 (Box Series I-1)
  - Aginsky, Burt W., 1970 (Box Series I-1)
    -See also Ser. I, American Anthropological Association
  - Aitken, Neil, 1969 (Box Series I-1)
  - Akwesasne Mohawk Counselor Organization, 1945, 1949, n.d. (Box Series I-1)
    Fadden, Ray
  - Akwesasne Notes, 1969-1970, 1972 (Box Series I-1)
    Gambill, Jerry
  - Albany College of Pharmacy, 1972 (Box Series I-1)
  - Albany Institute of History and Art, 1966 (Box Series I-1)
  - Albany Jewish Community Center, 1990 (Box Series I-1)
  - Aldine Publishing Co., 1969 (Box Series I-1)
  - Alexander, Joy, 1984 (Box Series I-1)
  - Alexander, Matt (Box Series I-1)
    -See Ser. I, Brandhorst, Bob
  - Alexander, William P., 1943 (Box Series I-1)
  - Allard, H.A., 1947 (Box Series I-1)
    Rehder, Harald A.
  - Allegany School of Natural History, 1939-1941 (Box Series I-1)
    Gordon, Robert B.
    Hamlin, Chauncey J.
    Seelye, Laurens H.
  - Allegheny College, 1968 (Box Series I-1)
  - Allen, Hope Emily, 1948 (Box Series I-1)
    -See also Oversized
  - Alspach, Russell, 1960 (Box Series I-1)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1949 (Box Series I-1)
  - American Anthropological Association, 1935-1984 (Box Series I-1)
    Aginsky, Burt W.
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box Series I-1)
    Barnett, H.G.
    Boggs, Stephen T.
    Cooper, John M.
    Ehrich, Robert W.
    Foster, George M.
    Fox, John W.
    Hoijer, Harry
    Hymes, Dell
    Lehman, Edward J.
    Murdock, George Peter
    Shapiro, Harry L.
    Stout, David B.
    Tax, Sol
    Voegelin, Erminie W.
    Woodbury, Nathalie F.S.
    Woodbury, Richard B.
    -See also Ser. I, Ehrich, Robert W.
    -See also Ser. I, Flick, Hugh M.
    -See also Ser. I, Tax, Sol
    -See also Ser. I, Washburn, Wilcomb
  - American Anthropologist, 1940-1972 (Box Series I-1)
    Mason, J. Alden
    Spindler, George D.
  - American Antiquarian Society, 1950 (Box Series I-1)
  - American Antiquity, 1945-1946, 1961 (Box Series I-1)
    Byers, Douglas S.
    Collier, Donald
  - American Archivist, 1958 (Box Series I-1)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1943, 1948 (Box Series I-1)
  - American Association on Indian Affairs, Inc. (Box Series I-1)
    -See Ser. I, Association on American Indian Affairs, Inc.
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1940-1944, 1962, 1980-1982 (Box Series I-1)
    Goodchild, Donald
    Graves, Mortimer
  - American Ethnological Society, 1958, 1970-1976, n.d. (Box Series I-1)
    Holmberg, Allan R.
    Kimball, Solon T.
  - American Ethnologist, 1992 (Box Series I-1)
    Abler, [Thomas S.]
  - The American Folklore Society, Inc., 1942-1989 (Box Series I-1)
    Davidson, D. Sutherland
    Dorson, Richard M.
    Hand, Wayland D.
    Leach, MacEdward
    -See also Ser. I, Bosch-Gimpera, P.
  - The American Herbal and Botanical Institute, 1943 (Box Series I-1)
  - American Historical Review, 1943, n.d. (Box Series I-1)
    Chalmers, Harvey II
  - American Indian Art Magazine, 1994 (Box Series I-1)
  - American Indian Community House, 1985 (Box Series I-1)
  - American Indian Culture and Research Journal, 1981-1991 (Box Series I-1)
  - American Indian Quarterly, 1987 (Box Series I-1)
  - American Jewish Museum of Art and Culture, 1969 (Box Series I-2)
  - American Museum of Fly Fishing, 1991 (Box Series I-2)
  - American Museum of Natural History, 1940-1984 (Box Series I-2)
    Freed, Stanley A.
    -See also Ser. I, Cardinal Lithographers, Inc.
  - American National Biography, 1992-1993 (Box Series I-2)
  - American Notes & Queries, 1946 (Box Series I-2)
  - American Philosophical Society (Box Series I-2)
    de Laguna, Frederica
    Delancey, Scott
    Freeman, John F.
    Hauptman, Laurence Marc
    Newhouse, Seth
    -See also Ser. I, Adams, Walter Randolph
    -See also Ser. I, Jacobs Research Funds
    -See also Ser. I, Kenneth Nebenzahl, Inc.
    -See also Ser. I, Snyderman, George S.
    -See also Ser. I, Sturtevant, William C.
    - Folder #1, 1947-1967 (Box Series I-2)
    - Folder #2, 1968-1984 (Box Series I-2)
  - American Society for Ethnohistory, 1968-1985 (Box Series I-2)
    Koehler, Lyle
    Snow, Dean R.
    Spores, Ronald
    -See also Ser. I, Ethnohistory
  - Americana Institute, 1941 (Box Series I-2)
    Fisk, H.E.
  - Amerindian, 1953 (Box Series I-2)
  - Anderson, Jerald H., 1992 (Box Series I-2)
  - Anderson, Myrdene, 1991 (Box Series I-2)
  - Andrews, David H., 1970 (Box Series I-2)
  - Annual Reviews, Inc., 1969 (Box Series I-2)
  - Anthropological Quarterly, 1975 (Box Series I-2)
  - Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith, 1949 (Box Series I-2)
  - Appell, George N., 1967-1969 (Box Series I-2)
  - Aquila, Richard, 1974 (Box Series I-2)
  - Archaeological Society of Delaware, 1944 (Box Series I-2)
    Weslager, C.A.
  - Archives de la Compagnie de Jésus, 1979 (Box Series I-2)
    some in French
  - The Archives of the Moravian Church, 1959 (Box Series I-2)
  - Arete Publishing Co., 1977 (Box Series I-2)
  - Arizona State Museum, 1986 (Box Series I-2)
  - Armstrong, Margaret E., 1948 (Box Series I-2)
  - Armstrong, William H., 1972 (Box Series I-2)
  - Arnason, Thor, 1980 (Box Series I-2)
  - Arts Club of Washington, 1946 (Box Series I-2)
  - Arum, Stephen, 1969 (Box Series I-2)
  - Ashton, J.W. (Box Series I-2)
    -See Ser. I, Indiana University
  - Assembly of First Nations, 1986 (Box Series I-2)
    British Museum
  - Association on American Indian Affairs, Inc., 1942-1953 (Box Series I-2)
    Carmer, Carl
    Emerson, Haven
    Hassrick, Royal B.
    McDermott, Patricia
    Solenberger, Robert Reeves
    -See also Ser. I, Madigan, LaVerne
  - Atkinson, Brooks, 1968 (Box Series I-2)
  - Averkieva, Yu.P., 1965 (Box Series I-2)
    Zolotarevskaja, I.A.
  - Avirom, Don, 1987 (Box Series I-2)
    Lowie Museum of Anthropology
  - Axtell, James, 1974-1993 (Box Series I-2)